export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The document which serves as evidence for the registration of a company is",
A: "articles of association.",
B: "certificate of incorporation.",
C: "certificate of trading.",
D: "memorandum of association.",
answer: "B. certificate of incorporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following activities comes first in a business decision-making process?",
A: "Identifying the problem",
B: "Gathering of information",
C: "Developing alternatives",
D: "Making a choice",
answer: "A. Identifying the problem",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The sets of programs which instruct a computer how to do a particular job is",
A: "database",
B: "hardware",
C: "memory",
D: "software",
answer: "D. software.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The means of exchanging goods for goods in international trade is",
A: "barter trade.",
B: "counter trade.",
C: "entrepot trade.",
D: "terms of trade",
answer: "A. barter trade",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The salaries paid to government employees are classified under",
A: "balance of payment.",
B: "capital account.",
C: "capital expenditure.",
D: "recurrent expenditure.",
answer: "D. capital expenditure.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A woman who smoke fish for sale is engaged in",
A: "direct service.",
B: "extractive industry.",
C: "indirect service.",
D: "manufacturing industry.",
answer: "B. extractive industry",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The channel through which policies are communicated to employees of an organization is",
A: "diagonal communication.",
B: "downward communication.",
C: "horizontal communication.",
D: "upward communication",
answer: "B. downward communication",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The elements of the marketing mix are:",
A: "promotion, advertising, sales and distribution.",
B: "production, procurement, sales and pricing.",
C: "pricing, production, personnel and purchasing.",
D: "product, price, promotion and place.",
answer: "D. product, price, promotion and place",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A refund by customs authority to an importer for duty already paid on goods re-exported is",
A: "customs drawback.",
B: "excise duty.",
C: "import duty.",
D: "sales tax.",
answer: "A. customs drawback",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The document of title to be presented to clear goods at the port is",
A: "bill of lading.",
B: "certificate of inspection.",
C: "certificate of origin.",
D: "consular invoice.",
answer: "A. bill of lading",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. In a partnership, the bankruptcy of a partner would lead to it’s",
A: "continuity",
B: "incorporation",
C: "liquidation",
D: "solvency",
answer: "C. liquidation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. An advantage of product branding to an organization is the",
A: "differentiation of items from similar products.",
B: "increased competition from other brands.",
C: "increased volume of production.",
D: "reduction in the cost of production.",
answer: "A. increased competition from other brands.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The end point towards which all organizations’ efforts are directed is",
A: "objective",
B: "policy",
C: "rule",
D: "strategy",
answer: "A. objective.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following activities is part of an organizing function of management?",
A: "Analysing the reasons for deviations",
B: "Determining the span of control",
C: "Formulating objectives and strategies",
D: "Providing motivation for employees",
answer: "B. Formulating objectives and strategies",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A step in production planning which gives a timetable for the commencement and completion of a job is",
A: "despatching",
B: "loading",
C: "routing",
D: "scheduling",
answer: "D. scheduling.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A contract under which a party undertakes to indemnify another against a risk is",
A: "assurance",
B: "insurance",
C: "partnership deed.",
D: "sale of goods.",
answer: "B. insurance.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Commercial banks lend money to individuals and firms in the form of",
A: "commission and dividends.",
B: "interest and profits.",
C: "loans and overdrafts.",
D: "shares and loans.",
answer: "C. loans and overdrafts.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. An objective of the labour union is to",
A: "the salary of its members.",
B: "organize strikes when there is misunderstanding.",
C: "rally active workers against government.",
D: "work towards better conditions for its members.",
answer: "D. Work towards better conditions for its members.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The use of one cheque to pay a number of people through a commercial bank is",
A: "credit transfer.",
B: "direct debit.",
C: "payment order.",
D: "standing order.",
answer: "C. payment order.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A current account holder is eligible for which of the following services?",
A: "Interest-free loan",
B: "Leasing facility",
C: "Overdraft facility",
D: "use of savings withdrawal form",
answer: "C. Overdraft facility.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The profits of a public corporation belong, to the",
A: "board of directors.",
B: "debenture holders.",
C: "government",
D: "shareholders",
answer: "C. government.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. An element in the law of contract is that",
A: "acceptance must be communicated.",
B: "all agreements must be sealed.",
C: "an offer must be moved by a promise.",
D: "principals should always ratify agents’ acts.",
answer: "A. acceptance must be communicated",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. In decision-making process, the step that determines the scope and use of resources to solve the problem falls under",
A: "analysis of the problem.",
B: "gathering of information.",
C: "development of alternatives.",
D: "evaluation of alternatives.",
answer: "D. evaluation of alternatives",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An organizational chart depicts",
A: "channels of informal communication.",
B: "the number of customers.",
C: "the number of employees.",
D: "the structure of an organization.",
answer: "D. the structure of an organisation.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The distribution function of marketing involves",
A: "product development and packaging.",
B: "production facilities and employee welfare.",
C: "segmentation and pricing policy.",
D: "transportation and warehousing.",
answer: "D. transportation and warehousing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The type of training which seeks to provide employees with work experience in all areas of the company’s operation is",
A: "apprenticeship",
B: "coaching",
C: "job rotation.",
D: "understudy assignment.",
answer: "C. job rotation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In a contract, an agreement is reached when an",
A: "offeror gives consideration.",
B: "offeror gives a promise.",
C: "offeree accepts the offer.",
D: "offeree declines the offer.",
answer: "C. offeree accepts the offer.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A reason for job interview is to",
A: "assess the suitability of applicants.",
B: "check the health status of the applicants.",
C: "give the applicant opportunity to introduce referees.",
D: "revise information given on the application form.",
answer: "A. assess the suitability of applicants",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. When the amount in words and figures differ on a cheque presented by a third party, the drawee will",
A: "ask the payee to make the necessary correction.",
B: "ask the payee to destroy the cheque.",
C: "dishonour and return the cheque to the drawer.",
D: "pay the higher amount to the payee.",
answer: "C. dishonor and return the cheque to the drawer.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Goods which consumers buy frequently in small quantities with less effort are",
A: "assorted goods.",
B: "capital goods.",
C: "convenience goods.",
D: "specialty goods.",
answer: "C. convenience goods.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. An advice note is issued by a seller to a buyer to inform him of the",
A: "amount due for payment.",
B: "arrival date of goods ordered.",
C: "available goods and terms of payment.",
D: "intention not to sell goods to him.",
answer: "B. arrival date of goods ordered",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The role of government in an economy is to",
A: "create enabling environment for businesses.",
B: "discourage foreign investments.",
C: "encourage foreign competition.",
D: "generate revenue for government officials.",
answer: "A. create enabling environment for businesses.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Marketing begins with the",
A: "selection of channels of distribution.",
B: "pricing of a product.",
C: "development of the product.",
D: "conception of the product.",
answer: "D. conception of the product.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The use of computers in a business is influenced by",
A: "legal factor.",
B: "political factor.",
C: "social factor.",
D: "technological factor.",
answer: "D. technological factor.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. When workers refuse to complete their tasks as a way of protest, this action is a form of",
A: "boycott",
B: "lobby",
C: "picketing",
D: "work-to-rule.",
answer: "D. work-to-rule.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A document issued by a seller to a buyer to inform him of his present indebtedness and the need to pay is",
A: "credit note.",
B: "debit note.",
C: "proforma invoice.",
D: "statement of accounts.",
answer: "D. Statement of accounts.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A sole proprietorship form of business changes to a partnership when",
A: "it acquires more capital and resources.",
B: "it employs more qualified workers.",
C: "it opens branches nationwide.",
D: "the number of its owners increases.",
answer: "D. the number of its owners increases.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following books will a business operator use to record smaller expenses?",
A: "Cash book",
B: "Petty cash book",
C: "Purchases day book",
D: "Sales day book",
answer: "B. Petty cash book",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The qualifications that a prospective employee must possess are contained in the job",
A: "enlargement",
B: "description",
C: "enrichment",
D: "specification",
answer: "B. description.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Lender of last resort is a function performed by the",
A: "central bank.",
B: "commercial bank.",
C: "community bank.",
D: "co-operative bank.",
answer: "A. central bank",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following, factors will ensure the survival of a business organization?",
A: "Its ability to produce in large quantities",
B: "Its ability to consistently make profits",
C: "The size of its community",
D: "The size of its equipment",
answer: "B. Its ability to consistently make profits",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The ultimate goal of the decision-making process is to",
A: "eliminate the root causes of the problem.",
B: "enable the choice of the best alternative.",
C: "identify the extra facts.",
D: "review the additional facts discovered.",
answer: "A. eliminate the root causes of the problem",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The collation and deployment of all resources needed by a business is part of the",
A: "controlling function.",
B: "directing function.",
C: "organizing function.",
D: "planning function.",
answer: "C. organising function.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following documents will be used when goods are transported by a courier company?",
A: "Consular invoice",
B: "Consignment note",
C: "Promissory note",
D: "Proforma invoice",
answer: "B. Consignment note.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A means of payment that is transferrable by mere delivery or delivery plus endorsement is",
A: "cross cheque.",
B: "legal tender.",
C: "money order.",
D: "negotiable instrument.",
answer: "D. negotiable instrument",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The manufacturing of automobiles is an example of",
A: "assembling production.",
B: "batch production.",
C: "flow production.",
D: "job production.",
answer: "A. assembling production",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the levels in Maslow’s hierarchy of needs is satisfied when a worker acquires food, shelter and clothing?",
A: "Physiological needs",
B: "Safety needs",
C: "Social needs",
D: "Esteem needs",
answer: "A. Physiological needs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Performance appraisal is a means of",
A: "assessing the popularity of employees.",
B: "evaluating the work of employees.",
C: "improving working conditions of employees.",
D: "monitoring the attendance of employees.",
answer: "B. evaluating the work of employees.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Budgets and plans are a form of",
A: "non-programmed decisions.",
B: "non-programmed operations.",
C: "programmed decisions.",
D: "programmed operations.",
answer: "C. programmed decisions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Penetration pricing strategy is used by producers when the product is",
A: "being introduced to the market.",
B: "being withdrawn from the market.",
C: "facing keen competition.",
D: "established in the market.",
answer: "A. being introduced to the market",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]